#### **OBJECTIVE**

Senior Full Stack Developer having 11+ Years of Experience in Web Development with the ability to create interactive responsive Websites and Web Applications. Moreover, the ability to deploy sites with DevOps tools and automate the process using CI/CD pipelines. Seeking a challenging position as Senior Full Stack Engineer/ AWS Cloud Developer with (AWS / MEAN / MERN) technologies in a reputed organization where I can utilize and improve my skills.

- 11+ years of total experience in web development with strong technical knowledge.
- 7+ years of experience with Single Page Application with Back End Application Design.
- 2+ Years of Experience in AWS Cloud Infrastructure and Development.
- Good Experience with Multiple Stacks like MEAN and MERN.
- Programming abilities across a range of languages like Angular 17, React JS 18, Node JS etc...
- Experience with different data format like JSON, XML, YAML
- Comprehensive understanding of and significant experience with Web Services and APIs
- Experience with Unit testing skills with Jasmine, karma, JUnit5 and Mockito.
- Strong understanding of version control (Git & GitHub)
- Good knowledge and hands on experience on Linux based operating systems with bash script
- Docker image building, maintenance, orchestration with Kubernetes and Jenkins pipelining
- Knowledge of Micro services architecture with Docker container implementation
- Continuous integration/Continuous delivery tools Jenkins Pipelines & GitHub Actions
- Experience in AWS multiple services & infrastructure creation with Terraform
- Able to work in an agile remote team with task-based deliveries.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Payroll Company	Client Company	Location	Experience (11+ Years)	
Taylor and Francis	Taylor and Francis	Bangalore	3+ Years (Sep 2021 to till now)	
Wipro Technologies	Cisco Systems	Bangalore	2.3 Years (July 2019 to Sep 2021)	
Bahwan CyberTek	PwC	Bangalore	2.1 Years (May 2017 to May 2019)	
RxPrism Health Systems	RxPrism Health Systems	Bangalore	10 Months (June 2016 to Mar 2017)	
Smackcoders Technologies	Smackcoders Technologies	Nellai	2.9 Years (Aug 2013 to Apr 2016)	

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Front End: HTML5, CSS3

Scripting Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, ES6, SASS, Bash

JavaScript Frameworks & Libraries: Angular 17, React JS 18, Next JS

UI Frameworks: Angular Material, Material UI, Tailwind, Bootstrap

Back End: Node.js, Express JS, Java 17, Spring Boot 3, Spring Cloud

JavaScript Libraries: RxJS, Redux, jQuery

Mobile Development: Ionic 3, Cordova

Database: Mongo DB, MySQL

Version Control: Git, GitHub

Unit Testing: Jasmine, Karma, JUnit, Mockito

Operating Systems: Linux, Mac and Windows

**DevOps:** Docker, Kubernetes, Jenkins, GitHub Actions and Terraform

AWS: EC2, S3, ECS, EKS, Elastic Beanstalk, Lambda, Serverless, VPC, IAM and etc.

## **ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION**

MCA	MIIT, Chennai	2008 - 2011	73%
ВСА	St. John's College, Tirunelveli	2005 - 2008	59%
12 <sup>th</sup>	Schaffter Hr. Sec. School, Tirunelveli	2004 - 2005	50%
10 <sup>th</sup>	Schaffter Hr. Sec. School, Tirunelveli	2002 - 2003	79%

#### **PORTFOLIO**

## Project #1

Project Name : Dynamic Book Submission Web

Company : Taylor and Francis
Role : Full Stack Developer

Environment : Angular 12, Node JS, Express JS

Responsibilities : Creating Application from Scratch for both Front End and Back End Project Description : An application let the Authors to submit and publish their Journals

Project #2

Project Name : PLDT BPA Company : Cisco Systems Role : Full Stack Developer

Environment : Angular 8, Node.js, Express.js, Mongo DB, Docker, Kubernetes

Responsibilities : Creating and Maintaining new Modules

Project Description : Networking Application in MEAN Stack. This application is to configure

Cisco and Huawei network devices.

Project #3

Project Name : Pharmacist Application

Company : PwC

Role : Backend Developer

Environment : Node.js, Express.js, Mongo DB

Responsibilities : Creating APIs

Storing and retrieving data from Mongo DB through APIs

Project Description : An application for Pharma companies, which is used to analyze

selling products and stocks.

Project #4

Project Name : Insights Platform

Company : PwC

Role : UI Developer

Environment : HTML5, CSS3, TypeScript, Angular 5

Responsibilities : Design and Develop

Debugging and fixing critical issues reported in UI

Project Description : Angular Application based on Data Science. User can import file as CSV or

Zip to analyze and this application generates the reports.

Project #5

Project Name : Melco Company : PwC

Role : UI Developer

Environment : HTML5, CSS3, TypeScript, Angular 2, Prime NG, Lodash

Responsibilities : Design and Develop (Front End, Business logic)

Debugging and fixing critical issues reported in UI

Project Description : Hong Kong based Casino Project.

### Project #6

Project Name : CCN Company : PwC

Role : UI Developer

Environment : HTML5, CSS3, Typescript, Angular 2, NG2 Google Charts Responsibilities : Creating charts with Google charts with given API response

Creating charts according to the filter criteria

Project Description : Chart application which is used to know process of multiple servers

by Charts

## Project #7

Project Name : Blocktricity Company : PwC

Role : Mobile Application Developer

Environment : IONIC 2

Responsibilities : Creating a responsive mobile application by IONIC components

Project Description : Electricity Online payment Mobile Application

### Project #8

Project Name : Call with Doctor

Company : RxPrism Health Systems
Role : React JS Developer
Environment : React JS, Cordova

Responsibilities : Creating a hybrid mobile app in native look and performance

Creating iOS and Android App with single development package.

Project Description : This mobile app allows patients to call Doctors for consulting

purpose within the App.

#### Project #9

Project Name : CSV Importer Plugin

Company : Smackcoders Technologies

Role : PHP Developer

Environment : HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, PHP, MySQL, WordPress Responsibilities : Creating WordPress plugin, Enhancements with additional features

Project Description : A WordPress plugin allows user to import and export data as CSV and XML

from/to WordPress site.

#### Project #10

Project Name : Smackcoders Technologies Official Site

Company : Smackcoders Technologies

Role : PHP Developer

Environment : HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, PHP, MySQL, WordPress

Responsibilities : Enhancements and creating new web pages

Maintaining checkout page with WordPress WooCommerce plugin

Project Description : Official site of the same company which is mostly used to sell

software products in their official site.

# PERSONAL SUMMARY

Languages Known	English & Tamil
Gender	Male
Date of Birth	01/02/1988
Religion	Muslim
Address	350, 1 <sup>st</sup> Floor, 6 <sup>th</sup> Cross street, Kodeeswaran Nagar, Tirunelveli Town, Pin code- 627006, Tamil Nadu, India
Mobile number	91-9790407040
Mail Id	mansoorkhanmca@gmail.com
Nationality	Indian